<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Weapons</name>
		<update version="0.0.5">
			<file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RapidCoyote/AdamDND/main/Andromadam/Andromeda/items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<!-- simple -->
	<element name="Recurve Bow" type="Weapon" source="Andromeda" id="ID_WOTC_PHB_WEAPON_RECURVE_BOW">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_Piercing, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_AMMUNITION, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_TWOHANDED, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_BOWS</supports>
		<description>
			<p></p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">25</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">twohand</set>
            <set name="range">80/320</set>
			<set name="damage" type="Piercing">1d6</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RECURVE</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

    <element name="Hama Yumi" type="Magic Item" source="Andromeda" id="ID_MAGIC_ITEM_HAMA_YUMI">
		<description>
			<p>A fine wooden bow, colored Red and black, the Hama Yumi has been passed down from the Yumiko Family for generations. With a single fire from an arrow, the Hama Yumi is said to banish the evil from within its target.</p>
			<sheet display="false"> <p class="indent"><b><i>Ability Score Increase. </i></b>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</p> </sheet>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Bane of all Evil. </i></b>If the enemy you are shooting with this bow is evil, the bow will do 3d10 extra radiant damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Delayed Strike. </i></b>On a critical hit, the arrow will be magically enhanced and wherever it lands, a delayed fireball will be cast there. You may choose to explode it as a bonus action. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Spells. </i></b>The Hama Yumi has 5 charges, which are recovered at dawn of the next day, and lets you cast; Detect Evil and Good(1 charge), Protection from Evil and Good(1 charge), and Dispel Evil and Good(3 charges)</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Damage. </i></b>The Hama Yumi does 4d6 Piercing damage, and 3d10 Radiant damage if the target is evil.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties. </i></b>The Hama Yumi has been cursed by an ancient Evil, cursing the user with some detrimental effects.</p>
			<li>
				<ul>3 minor beneficial properties</ul>
				<ul>1 major beneficial property</ul>
				<ul>2 minor detrimental properties</ul>
				<ul>1 major detrimental property</ul>
			</li>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Recurve Bow</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="Recurve Bow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="weapon">Recurve Bow</set>
			<set name="damage">4d6</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dexterity" value="2"/>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1"/>
			<stat name="dexterity:max" value="2" />
			<stat name="wisdom:max" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Necklace of Mirages" type="Magic Item" source="Andromeda" id="ID_MAGIC_ITEM_NECKLACE_OF_MIRAGES">
		<description>
			<p>A beautiful silver pendant created by the trickery god Dolus, the pendant looks like two silver wings emerging from an ovular Sapphire in the center, 3 chains emerging from the tips of the angel's wings, all to a small clasp on the end to fit the pendant perfectly to your neck.</p>
			<sheet display="false"> <p class="indent"><b><i>Ability Score Increase. </i></b>Your Wisdom score increases by 2.</p> </sheet>
			<sheet action="Action"> <p class="indent"><b><i>Mirage. </i></b>Create a perfect mirror image of yourself. If you make an action, bonus action, or reaction, the mirage will follow your movements perfectly, if you do a ranged attack, the mirage will also make one, dealing half of your rolled damage on a hit (uses your roll), if casting an offensive spell, the mirage will also cast said spell, directed to wherever you casted it to (dealing half damage). The mirage lasts for 1 hour and this feature.</p> </sheet>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Illusionist's delight. </i></b>You may cast every Illusion spell from 1st to 9th level once/per long rest, and every cantrip infinitely.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Mayhem. </i></b>You may cast delayed blast fireball at 9th level once per long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties. </i></b>The Necklace of Mirages has some randome properties</p>
			<li>
				<ul>2 minor beneficial properties</ul>
				<ul>2 major beneficial properties</ul>
				<ul>1 minor detrimental property</ul>
			</li>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="12">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
            <stat name="wisdom" value="2"/>
			<stat name="wisdom:max" value="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Aegis" type="Magic Item" source="Andromeda" id="ID_MAGIC_ITEM_SHIELD_AEGIS">
		<description>
			<p>Created by the best blacksmiths in the Norman Empire, Aegis was created for a legendary fighter to assist him in defeating an evil Warlock. Aegis has an innate +2.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Magic Parry. </i></b>Whether it be a fireball, lightning strike, or even a charm, the Aegis can parry it. Allows you to cast Counter spell at 9th level once/per short rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Magic Resistance. </i></b>If a spellcaster targets you with a ranged/melee spell, they have disadvantage to hit, but if it is a spell save dc, then you have advantage. The shield's resistance to magic has also granted it immunity to heat metal.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:shield" value="2" bonus="enhancement" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Excalibur (Dormant)" type="Magic Item" source="Andromeda" id="ID_MAGIC_ITEM_EXCALIBUR_DORMANT">
		<description>
			<p><b><i>Infinite. </i></b> When the first of the Apeirons fell, He was there. When the first god, Elara created herself, He was there. When the first death of a god happened, He was there. Every. Single. Time.</p>
			<p>Excalibur has reached a dormant state, the blade was once sentient, but the original soul has all but dissolved over time.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Ability Score Increase. </i></b>Your Strength and Constitution scores increase by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Damage. </i></b>Excalibur does 2d6 Slashing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Sealing Strike. </i></b>On a Critical hit, You thrust Excalibur into your target dealing 4d6 true piercing damage, They must succeed a dc15 Wisdom saving throw or take 10d12 Radiant damage, this damage is treated as true damage. If this attack brings the target below 100 hit points, their soul is absorbed into the sword and they cannot be revived through any mean until their soul escapes the blade.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Proficiency. </i></b>If you bond with Excalibur You gain proficiency with Scimitars, if you already have proficiency with them, you gain Expertise with Excalibur.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Spells. </i></b>Excalibur has 3 charges, which are recovered at dawn of the next day, and lets you cast; Shield(1 charge), Banishment(1 charge), and Banishing Smite(2 charges)</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Curse. </i></b>The Apeiron has cursed Excalibur, once attuned the only way for you to unattune from the blade would be to either destroy the curse, destroy the blade, or die. Every so often Whispers of Retribution will plague your mind.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties. </i></b>Excalibur Inhibits the Ancient soul of a weathered Apeiron, Cursing the blade to forever carry the curse of The Old one's will.</p>
			<li>
				<ul>2 minor beneficial properties</ul>
				<ul>1 major beneficial property</ul>
				<ul>4 minor detrimental properties</ul>
				<ul>2 major detrimental properties</ul>
			</li>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Scimitar</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="Scimitar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="weapon">Scimitar</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="1"/>
			<stat name="strength:max" value="1" />
			<stat name="constitution" value="1"/>
			<stat name="constitution:max" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Excalibur (Awakened)" type="Magic Item" source="Andromeda" id="ID_MAGIC_ITEM_EXCALIBUR_AWAKENED">
		<description>
			<p><b><i>Eternal. </i></b>His choice was made. His children were slaughtered. cursed to forever walk the realms, forever in undeath. That was the sacrifice he chose to make.</p>
			<p>Excalibur has reached an awakened state, Whatever you did caused the beginning of the revivification.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Ability Score Increase. </i></b>Your Strength and Constitution scores increase by 1 and your Wisdom score increases by 2.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Damage. </i></b>Excalibur does 3d6 Slashing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Sealing Strike. </i></b>On a Critical hit, You thrust Excalibur into your target dealing 6d6 true piercing damage, They must succeed a dc20 Wisdom saving throw or take 12d12 Radiant damage, this damage is treated as true damage. If this attack brings the target below 100 hit points, their soul is absorbed into the sword and they cannot be revived through any mean until their soul escapes the blade.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Proficiency. </i></b>If you bond with Excalibur You gain proficiency with Scimitars, if you already have proficiency with them, you gain Expertise with Excalibur.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Spells. </i></b>Excalibur has 6 charges, which are recovered at dawn of the next day, and lets you cast; Shield(1 charge), Banishment(1 charge), Banishing Smite(2 charges), and Heal(4 charges),</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Curse. </i></b>The Apeiron has cursed Excalibur, once attuned the only way for you to unattune from the blade would be to either destroy the curse, destroy the blade, or die. Every so often Whispers of Retribution will plague your mind.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Soul Absorb. </i></b>You may cast Soul cage once per long rest, you do not need a cage as Excalibur acts as the cage instead.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Release. </i></b>Randomly release one soul from the Blade, roll a d12 to decide the creatures type, The creature is teated as incorporeal and as such, is resistant to non-magical physical attacks, but is vurnable to Radiant (even if it's a celestial), The creature will have no more tahn a 10cr.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties. </i></b>Excalibur Inhibits the Ancient soul of a weathered Apeiron, Cursing the blade to forever carry the curse of The Old one's will.</p>
			<li>
				<ul>3 minor beneficial properties</ul>
				<ul>1 major beneficial property</ul>
				<ul>2 minor detrimental properties</ul>
				<ul>1 major detrimental properties</ul>
			</li>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Scimitar</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="Scimitar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="weapon">Scimitar</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="1"/>
			<stat name="strength:max" value="1" />
			<stat name="constitution" value="1"/>
			<stat name="constitution:max" value="1" />
			<stat name="wisdom" value="2"/>
			<stat name="wisdom:max" value="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Excalibur (Exalted)" type="Magic Item" source="Andromeda" id="ID_MAGIC_ITEM_EXCALIBUR_EXALTED">
		<description>
			<p><b><i>Ouroboros. </i></b>How many Times have we been here? Done this? When does the cycle end? Or has it already? We sit here, drifting through the domain of Eternity, waiting for an answer from him.</p>
			<p>Excalibur has reached an Exalted state, Aeternitas resides within the blade, thanks to you, it's purpose now revivified like a burning phoenix.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Ability Score Increase. </i></b>Your Strength and Constitution scores increase by 1 and your Wisdom and Dexterity scores increase by 2.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Damage. </i></b>Excalibur does 4d6 Slashing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Sealing Strike. </i></b>On a Critical hit, You thrust Excalibur into your target dealing 8d6 true piercing damage, They must succeed a dc28 Wisdom saving throw or take 15d12 Radiant damage, this damage is treated as true damage. If this attack brings the target below 100 hit points, their soul is absorbed into the sword and they cannot be revived through any mean until their soul escapes the blade.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Proficiency. </i></b>If you bond with Excalibur You gain proficiency with Scimitars, if you already have proficiency with them, you gain Expertise with Excalibur.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Spells. </i></b>Excalibur has 9 charges, which are recovered at dawn of the next day, and lets you cast; Shield(1 charge), Banishment(1 charge), Banishing Smite(2 charges), Heal(4 charges), and Imprisonment(6 charges)</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Soul Absorb. </i></b>You may cast Soul cage once per long rest, you do not need a cage as Excalibur acts as the cage instead.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Release. </i></b>once per long rest you may Release Aeternitas from the blade for 1 minute.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>SealBreaker. </i></b>Excalibur's slashes break through the fabric of reality, letting you hit incoporeal enemies as if they were right there, and you are immune to Curses, Diseases, and Mind Control of any kind.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Double edged sword. </i></b>At will as a bonus action, you may Break Excalibur into two shorter blades, they have the light property, and you may give the left one to any willing creature if you so choose, You have expertise in both of them, the left one is treated as a shortsword that deals 2d6 piercing damage, and the right deals 3d6 slashing damage, And if either attack crits when you have both weapons in your hands, you may stab them both into a target, dealing 20d12 true radiant damage and sealing the target if they go below 100hp with this attack, subsequent crits during that turn deal 10d12 instead.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Psychic Connection. </i></b>You have a connection to the blade, once per long rest, if you are below 10% health, you may as an action lash out with pure magic, dealing 1d10 of every damage type around you (skipping allies) in a 30ft radius, completely and utterly destroying the soul of any creature you kill with this attack, any survivors will be frightened (no immunity) and attempt to flee from you for the next minute.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties. </i></b>The curse is broken, and the sword is cleansed.</p>
			<li>
				<ul>4 minor beneficial properties</ul>
				<ul>2 major beneficial property</ul>
			</li>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Scimitar</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="Scimitar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="weapon">Scimitar</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="1"/>
			<stat name="strength:max" value="1" />
			<stat name="constitution" value="1"/>
			<stat name="constitution:max" value="1" />
			<stat name="wisdom" value="2"/>
			<stat name="wisdom:max" value="2" />
			<stat name="dexterity" value="2"/>
			<stat name="dexterity:max" value="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ouroboros" type="Magic Item" source="Andromeda" id="ID_MAGIC_ITEM_RING_OF_OUROBOROS">
		<description>
			<p>This Ring seems to be made out of refined lonsdaleite, giving it a dark purple shimmer, and the wyrm has eyes made out of tiny diamonds, which no matter where they are, seem to shimmer with pure magic. In addition, the Ring itself seems to be a Wyrm in an interlocking cycle of biting it's own tail.</p>
			<p class="indent">While wearing this ring, You have advantage on all death saving throws.</p>
			<p class="indent">The ring has 5 charges. It regains 1d4 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn. Spells cast from the ring have a save DC of 17.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ring of Air Elemental Command.</em></strong> You can expend 2 of the ring's charges to cast <em>dominate monster</em> on an air elemental. In addition, when you fall, you descend 60 feet per round and take no damage from falling. You can also speak and understand Auran.</p>
			<p>If you help slay an air elemental while attuned to the ring, you gain access to the following additional properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You have resistance to lightning damage.</li>
				<li>You have a flying speed equal to your walking speed and can hover.</li>
				<li>You can cast the following spells from the ring, expending the necessary number of charges: <em>chain lightning</em> (3 charges), <em>gust of wind</em> (2 charges), or <em>wind wall</em> (1 charge).</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" />
			<stat name="speed:fly" value="speed" bonus="base" />
			<!-- todo: add flag for can hover? -->
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
